newharbinger.com 2019-05-04

# Privacy Policy | NewHarbinger.com

###  New Harbinger Takes Data Privacy Seriously

New Harbinger Publications, Inc., its subsidiaries, and its affiliates (collectively “New Harbinger,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) understand that you care about how your personal information is collected, used, stored, and shared. We take your privacy and our obligations to protect your data seriously. 

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, store, and share, and use your personal information, _and_ how you can exercise your privacy rights. This Privacy Policy applies to any information that you provide to us or that we collect about you when you visit the New Harbinger Website. If you have questions, we would love to answer them! Our contact information is listed at the end of this Privacy Policy.

####  Acceptance of Terms

By using our Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and our accompanying Terms and Conditions of Use Agreement.  **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE AGREEMENT, PLEASE DO NOT USE THE WEBSITE AND EXIT IT NOW.**

By accessing and using our Website, you acknowledge and agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use Agreement, and any future amendments and additions to this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use Agreement as published from time to time on the Website. Because our Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions of Use are updated periodically, please check back on a regular basis for any new updates.

If we make material changes to our Privacy Policy and privacy practices, we will attempt to provide you with notice of these changes by sending a notice to your email address (if provided to us) or making a prominent posting on our Website. To the extent required by law, we will obtain your consent to any new Privacy Policy.

####  Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

New Harbinger collects information when you visit our Website, create an account, buy a product through our Website, post a comment, sign up for a newsletter, request a print catalog, complete a survey, and sign up for a promotion or an event. Some of this information is what we traditionally think about as personally identifiable information about you and some of the information is technical information automatically logged by our servers. The amount and type of information that we gather depends on the nature of the interaction, the type of information you provide, and whether you consent to the use of cookies.

We collect information outlined both directly from you and, if you consent to the use of cookies, indirectly through the collection of information by third-party service providers that furnish services to New Harbinger and collect information about how users interact with our Website (collectively, “Service Providers”). For example, if you accept cookies—which you do not have to do—our Service Providers may collect track your activity on our Website and share that data with us.

**By using our Website and supplying any information to us, you authorize us to collect, use, store and otherwise process any personally identifiable information which relates to and identifies you, as well as potential personally identifiable information and technical information to the extent reasonably necessary to provide you with the ability to use and interact with our Website as well as to advertise and market our products to you.**

  1. **Personally Identifiable Information Collected**

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, personally identifiable information (“PII”) means any information or set of information that identifies or could be used by or on behalf of New Harbinger, or any of our Service Providers, to identify a natural person.  Traditional examples of PII include your name, home address, phone number, birth date, place of birth, Social Security Number, state identification numbers (e.g, driver’s license number), work place, and school. Some states and countries consider your email address, metadata, and Internet Protocol (“IP”) address to be PII; we refer to that type of information here as “Potential PII.”

PII does not include information that is encrypted, anonymized, or publicly available information that has not been combined with non-public PII.

Here are the types of interactions in which we collect PII:

    * _Create an account_.  A user who creates an account must provide his or her email address, state whether he or she is a mental health provider and create a password. You may—but are not required to—provide and store in your account your first and last name, phone number, shipping addresses, and billing information (credit card information and billing address). We will process this information based on your consent. 

A user must create an account in order to purchase a product or post a comment.

    * _Purchase a product.   _A user who purchases products online through the Website must create an account and provide the following information: their billing and shipping address(es) and credit card information. We will process this information based on your consent and to complete your purchase. 
      * If you want to receive emails from us about topics that relate to your purchase, then you can push a button to receive such communications while you are completing your purchase.
    * _Post a comment._   A user who wishes to post a comment on an article, video, or blog posted on the Website, must sign in to their account to do so. We will process this information based on your consent.
    * _Sign up for the newsletter._   A user who wishes to sign up for the New Harbinger newsletter must provide their email address. Note that we have several different newsletters on different topics. If you sign up for our general newsletter about upcoming books and events, we will not send you any other newsletters on specific topics unless you ask us to do so. We will process this information based on your consent, to facilitate your request for a newsletter, and our legitimate interest in promoting our business.
    * _Request a print catalog.   _A user who wishes to receive a New Harbinger catalog must provide their first and last name, email address, and mailing address. We will process this information based on your consent, to facilitate your request for a print catalog, and our legitimate interest in promoting our business.
    * _Complete a survey_.  A user who wishes to complete a survey will be asked to provide only the information needed to complete the survey in addition to responding to the questions asked. Some surveys are anonymous while others require users to provide first name and last name, email address and sometimes mailing address. We will process this information based on your consent.
    * _Sign up for a promotion or event.   _A user who wishes to participate in a promotion or an event will be asked to provide the following information: first name and last name, email address and sometimes a mailing address. We will process this information based on your consent, to facilitate your request, and our legitimate interest in promoting our business.

New Harbinger does not collect PII and/or Potential PII other than as described herein and below with respect to cookies. **Users to our Website can always refuse to supply PII, Potential PII, or Other Information (defined below) with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain sections and features of the Website.**

  2. **Cookies and Other Information Collected**

New Harbinger also collects other information that is not PII or Potential PII that web browsers and servers typically make available if you consent to the use of cookies on our Website.  **We do not infer consent, rather you must click the “Approve Cookies” button on our pop up banner for cookies to be activated while you are on our Website.   You do not have to accept the use of cookies to use our Website, but cookies that are necessary to make our Website function and allow us to identify misuse will be active even if you do not accept cookies.  We may combine cookies data with other PII or Potential PII that we may have collected about you.**

A cookie is a string of information that a Website stores on a user’s computer, and that the user’s browser provides to the Website each time the user returns.

We use collecting information through cookies in order to:

    * Better understand how users access and interact with our Website as well as the types of products searched for on the Website.
    * Store items in your shopping cart.
    * Recognize when you return to our Website.
    * Understand where issues may arise on our Website and engage in troubleshooting.
    * Improve our customer service operations.

You may consent to the use of cookies on our Website by clicking the “Accept Cookies” button on the popup banner. If you accept cookies, then we and our Service Providers will collect information about you. The types of information we will collect about you if you consent to the use of cookies includes: the browser type, language preference, the date and time of each user request, your IP address, a guess on where you are located in the world based on your IP address, the amount of time spent on particular pages or sections of the Website, the number of links clicked on while on the Website, any search terms used while on the Website, the website that referred you to our Website, and technical information about your mobile device, if applicable (“Other Information”).

If you consent to the use of cookies, we will combine any PII or Potential PII that you provide to us with Other Information that we collect about you. If you later change your mind, you can request that we delete such information and we will comply with your request to the extent possible. See “Your Privacy Rights” below.

**Not Accepting Cookies.   **If you do not accept cookies, then we and our Service Providers will not track how you interact with our Website other than if you request that we send you information, then we will capture the data you enter into the Website to facilitate your request (e.g. sign you up for our newsletter if you provide us with your contact information and a request to receive the newsletter).

Even if you do not accept the use of cookies on our Website, we will still use functional cookies. Our functional cookies are cookies that are only set by us, not by a third party. We use functional cookies to:

    * Permit our Website to function.
    * Allow your browser to store our Website as a website that you have previously visited.
    * Maintain your shopping cart during a session or visit to our Website.
    * List products recently viewed by you during your current session.
    * Maintain a session.
    * For security purposes.

If you do not accept cookies, then to the extent these cookies collecting PII, Potential PII, and/or Other Information about you that personally identifies you, such information will be stored only during your visit to our Website to ensure the Website functions properly, e.g., products you place in your cart will stay there during your session.  Once you end your visit to our Website, the cookies that will be maintained will not capture any of your PII, Potential PII, or Other Information.

  3. **Do Not Track Signals**. New Harbinger does not respond to web browser “do not track” signals or other mechanisms that permits an individual to exercise choice regarding the collection of PII, Potential PII, and Other Information about that individual’s activities over time and across third-party websites and online services.  Some of the Service Providers who run cookies on our Website respond to “do not track” signals.

####  Use and Disclosure of PII, Potential PII, and Other Information

**NEW HARBINGER WILL NOT RENT OR SELL YOUR INFORMATION TO ANYONE.**

New Harbinger will trade a list of users who have purchased products from us as well as the users’ contract information with similar publishing companies to use for advertising purposes. You may let us know that you do not want us to share your PII or Potential PII with these other publishing company by emailing us at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests).  Alternatively, you can call us at 510-652-0215.

  1. **How New Harbinger Uses Your Information**

We use your PII, Potential PII, and Other Information for the following purposes:

    * To interact with you via the Website, in emails, at conferences, and at other in-person events.
    * To process and track any purchases that you make.
    * To send you newsletters or information about certain events when you request such information.
    * To market services and products to you based on PII, Potential PII, and Other Information that you provide to us. For example, if you tell us you are interested in mindfulness and sign up for emails on that topic, we will send you a promotion for books about that topic or a catalog with books about that topic. **Please note that marketing materials may come from us, our Service Providers, or other publishing companies, with whom we share Users’ contact information.**
    * To understand your topic preferences. For example, when you browse books in a certain category on our website, we may display product recommendations in related categories.
    * To better understand how you and other users access, interact with, and use our Website and social media accounts, as well as how we can improve our Website and develop and deliver new services and content.
    * To enhance our publication decisions.
    * To investigate any suspicious and/or illegal activities, as well as any potential violations of this Privacy Policy or Terms and Conditions of Use.
    * To comply with our legal obligations.
  2. **Who Has Access to Information Collected by New Harbinger**

New Harbinger discloses PII, Potential PII, and Other Information to its employees, contractors and Service Providers that:

    * Need to know that information in order to process such information or provide services on our Websites on New Harbinger’s behalf; or
    * Have agreed to protect your PII, Potential PII, and Other Information in accordance with our privacy practices

If you provide PII, Potential PII, or Other Information to us, then we or our Service Providers may use this information to market services and products to you. Our Service Providers include Authorize, Google Analytics, ConvertCart, and Hotjar.

    * Authorize.net is a PCI-compliant entity that collects all billing information to process any orders that you may process on our Website and processes such information. 
    * Google Analytics collects anonymized data about how users access and interact with our Website.
    * ConvertCart collects users’ email addresses and any items in a shopping cart in order to email a user if a user forgets to check out. ConvertCart also captures any information that a user may provide during a survey completed on our Website. (<https://app.convertcart.com/docs/tracking-cookie>) 
    * Hotjar collects anonymized data about how users access and interact with our Website. (<https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/cookie-information>)

Some of our employees, contractors and Service Providers may be located outside of your home country. By using New Harbinger’s Website, you consent to the transfer of your PII, Potential PII, and Other Information to our employees, contractors, and Service Providers outside of your home country. Any transfer of data outside of your home country will be protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

New Harbinger also discloses the names and contact information of users who have purchased products from our Website with other publishers. These other publishers may use that information to directly market to users. If you tell us that you do not want to share your information with other publishers, then we will comply with your request.

New Harbinger might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, sale of assets, dissolution, or similar event, PII, Potential PII, and Other Information may be part of the transferred assets. In such an event, PII, Potential PII, and Other Information will remain protected by applicable privacy laws.

Other than as described above, New Harbinger discloses PII, Potential PII, and Other Information only:

    * When required to do so by law, court order, or a government agency.
    * To respond to any legal claims or demands brought against us.
    * To enforce our Terms and Conditions of Use, Privacy Policy, and any other contract to which we may be a party.
    * To investigate suspicious or potentially illegal activity.
    * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property, rights, or safety of New Harbinger, third parties or the public at large.

New Harbinger takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of PII, Potential PII, and Other Information.

####  Financial Transactions

Any purchases made on the Website are processed by Authorize.net. When you enter billing information, such as your credit card number, expiration date, and billing address in to purchase a book from us, this information is actually collected and processed by Authorize.net. Authorize.net is a PCI compliant entity. New Harbinger does not collect, store, or maintain any financial information, unless you choose to store financial information in your account. Rather, once your financial information is processed, Authorize.net informs us the transaction is complete and we will ship you your purchases.

####  Communications from New Harbinger

If you have supplied your email address to us for future communications, New Harbinger may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new available information, books, surveys, and events, or to solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with New Harbinger.

All emails and newsletters from our Website allow you to opt out of further mailings.

####  Your Privacy Rights

  * _Right of Access_.  You have the right to know that we are processing your PII, Potential PII and Other Information, how we are processing this information, and for what purposes.  This Privacy Policy is intended to address those points, but you can certainly make additional inquiries to New Harbinger by emailing [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests) or you can call us at 510-652-0215.
  * _Update Your Account.   _You may edit and update your account information by signing into your account on the Website. If you click “User Profile,” you can update your user name, billing information, and shipping information. If you click “Account Settings,” you can update your email address and password.
  * _Right to Modify Your Information_.  You may correct any inaccurate information, modify any information about yourself that you have provided to New Harbinger—whether that information was provided to us at our Website, in person at a book fair, or over the phone—and to supplement incomplete information by sending us an email at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests) with your name and what information you would like modified. Alternatively, you can call us at 510-652-0215.
  * _Delete Your Information_.  You may request that we delete any or all the information that you have provided about yourself to New Harbinger—whether that information was provided to us at our Website, in person at a book fair, or over the phone— by emailing us at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests).  Alternatively, you can call us at 510-652-0215.
  * _Restrict How Your Information is Used_.  You may request that we restrict how we use and process your PII, Potential PII, and Other Information by emailing us at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests).  For example, you may request that we no longer share your name and mailing address with other publishing companies who sell products and services similar to those offered by New Harbinger by emailing us.  Alternatively, you can call us at 510-652-0215.
  * _Transfer Your Information_.  If you desire to transfer any and all data that you have provided to us, please let us know by emailing us at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests). Alternatively, you can call us at 510-652-0215. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to transfer such data in a secure manner. Please be aware that not all states and countries provide for the same legal protections of data.
  * _Right to Withdraw Consent_.  Where you have given consent to us to process your PII, Potential PII, or Other Information, you have the right to withdraw that consent and we will promptly respond. You can exercise this right by sending us an email at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests) with your name and the information for which you ware withdrawing your consent or by calling us at 510-652-0215.
  * _Right to Object to Processing.   _You have the right to object to our processing of your PII, Potential PII, or Other Information which is based on New Harbinger’s legitimate interest in running, maintaining, and developing our business. **Particularly, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal information related to direct marketing communications.** Upon receiving an objection from you, New Harbinger will cease to process your information. You can exercise this right by sending us an email at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests) with your name and the basis for your objection or by calling us at 510-652-0215.
  * _No Automated Decision-Making.   _On our Website, we do not use automated decision-making—which means using information that we know about you to make a decision about you that will significantly affect your legal interest.

We will use commercially reasonable efforts to process users’ requests in a timely manner. You should be aware, however, that it is not always possible to completely modify or totally delete information in our databases. 

####  Security

New Harbinger takes commercially reasonable steps to protect PII, Potential PII, and Other Information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.  Whenever we collect PII, Potential PII, and Other Information on our Website, that information is encrypted while in transit and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a lock icon in the address bar and looking for “https” at the beginning of the address of the Website. We are working towards encrypting our data at rest, as well.

Please understand, however, that no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our databases, nor can we guarantee that the information you provide to or through our Website or email will not be intercepted while being transmitted to and from us over the internet. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via email.

You should also engage in safe practices, such as: choosing a strong password that you do not share with others, using secure devices and networks, logging out of your account at the end of a session, and using reasonable caution.

####  Records

New Harbinger takes commercially reasonable steps to dispose of user’s records containing PII that are within our custody when such records are no longer required. We retain records to the extent required by applicable law and for only the time period required by applicable law. We also comply with applicable laws regarding the maintenance, storage, and destruction of records containing PII or Potential PII. Steps to dispose of records may include shredding, erasing, or otherwise modifying the PII or Potential PII in those records to make it unreadable or undecipherable through any means.

####  Third Party Companies and Websites

The privacy practices provided in this Privacy Policy are for this Website only. The Website may contain links to third-party websites. New Harbinger has no control over the content, Terms and Conditions of Use, or privacy practices of those websites. Therefore, we are not responsible for the content, Terms and Conditions of Use, or privacy practices of those websites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Website and to read the Terms and Conditions of Use and privacy statements of any other website that you may visit.

This Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use do not apply to the practices of companies that New Harbinger does not own or control, or to people that New Harbinger does not employ or manage.

####  Children

New Harbinger does not knowingly collect PII, Potential PII, or Other Information from children under the age of 18 years old through our Website.  **IF YOU ARE UNDER 18 YEARS OLD, PLEASE DO NOT PROVIDE NEW HARBINGER WITH ANY POTENTIAL PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION, PERSONAL IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION OR ANY OTHER INFORMATION.**

We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children to never provide PII, Potential PII, or Other Information through any website without the permission of a parent or guardian. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 18 has provided PII, Potential PII, or Other Information to us, please contact us and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases.

####  California Residents

It is New Harbinger’s policy to disclose our users’ names and contact information that we collect with other publishing companies that sell similar products to us for direct marketing purposes. California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-.84 requires that all California residents be afforded the option to exercise your choice of whether your PII may be shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes or not, as well as to receive information specified in the statute if your PII is disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Accordingly, if you are a California resident and you wish to inform New Harbinger whether you permit or refuse the sharing of your PII with third parties for direct marketing purposes, or if you wish to request certain information of your PII to be disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes, please contact us at [Data Privacy Requests](https://www.newharbinger.com/data-privacy-requests) or calling us at 510-652-0215.

####  Location of Processing of PII, Potential PII, and Other Information

Your PII, Potential PII, and Other Information will be used, stored, processed, or shared in the United States, where privacy laws may be less stringent than the laws in your country and where the government, courts, or law enforcement may be able to access your PII, Potential PII, and Other Information.  By submitting your PII, Potential PII, and Other Information to us you agree to transfer, storage, and processing of your PII, Potential PII, or Other Information in the United States.

####  Privacy Policy Changes

This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date stated at the top of this Privacy Policy. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time in our sole discretion.  Modifications shall become effective immediately upon being posted on this Website.  Please be aware that, to the extent permitted by applicable law, our use of PII, Potential PII, and Other Information is governed by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time we collect the information. We encourage users to frequently check this page for any changes to this Privacy Policy.

####  Other Forms of Communication

We may also communicate with you via in-person meetings, phone, and at conferences.  If we collect from you Potential PII or PII about you from those interactions, we will store that information in our servers and information system in a commercially reasonable manner.

####  How to Contact Us

If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our Privacy Policy you may contact us using the information below:

By e-mail: [privacy@newharbinger.com](mailto:privacy@newharbinger.com)  
By phone: 510-652-0215

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy.  Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted.

####  Complaints

If you have any complaints, please contact us using the information above.  Alternatively, you can contact the Attorney General of the State of California at 720-508-6000 or file a complaint with the Attorney General of the State of California [here](https://oag.ca.gov/contact/general-comment-question-or-complaint-form). If you are in the European Union, you can contact United Kingdom’s Information Commissioner’s Office at 0303-123-1133.

End of Policy

Last Updated: January 18, 2019
